[
    {
        "question": "The rainforests are rightly called the ................ .",
        "options": [
            "Roof of the world",
            "Heaven of the world",
            "Lungs of the world",
            "Desert of the world"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "In the swampy areas of the Assam huge ................ are found.",
        "options": [
            "One horned rhinoceroses",
            "Tiger",
            "Elephants",
            "Monkey"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the odd man out: With reference to fauna of Brazil",
        "options": [
            "Anaconda",
            "Tamarin",
            "Red Panda",
            "Lion"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "The ever green forests of India are found ................ rainfall region.",
        "options": [
            "1000mm",
            "2000mm",
            "3000mm",
            "4000mm"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Identified the odd man out: With reference to India",
        "options": [
            "Mangrove forests",
            "Mediterranean forests",
            "Thorny bush-type vegetation",
            "Equatorial forests"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country a greater diversity of vegetation is found? What is the reason is behind it?",
        "options": [
            "India",
            "Brazil",
            "China",
            "USA"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country do equatorial forests occupy a greater area",
        "options": [
            "India",
            "Brazil",
            "China",
            "USA"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "On which coast do you mainly find the coastal vegetation?",
        "options": [
            "Western",
            "Eastern",
            "Northern",
            "Southern"
        ],
        "answer":2
    },
    {
        "question": "Brazil has the largest number of ............... species in the world",
        "options": [
            "Flowers",
            "Vegetation",
            "Birds",
            "Above All"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "In Brazil, rainfall varies due to ................ .",
        "options": [
            "Climate",
            "Physiography",
            "Vegetation",
            "Forests"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "In the swampy areas of the Pantanal huge ................. are found.",
        "options": [
            "Pigs",
            "Crocodiles",
            "Anacondas",
            "Horse"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "The swampy areas near the coastal areas having saline soil are called ................ in India.",
        "options": [
            "Kharland",
            "Sundarbans",
            "Dryland",
            "Wetland"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Which forests are found in western snow-capped regions.",
        "options": [
            "Sahara",
            "Thar",
            "Cold",
            "Hot"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do you find thorny and shrub vegetation found in India?",
        "options": [
            "Central",
            "Northern",
            "Southern",
            "Eastern"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of forests found in India are not found in Brazil",
        "options": [
            "Evergreen Forests",
            "Deciduous Forests",
            "Coastal Forests",
            "Himalayan Forests"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    }
]